<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2022-11-21T08:34:26.882+05:30"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="admin"
        cq:template="/conf/capstone/settings/wcm/templates/page-content"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="Article"
        sling:resourceType="capstone/components/page">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="capstone/components/container"
            layout="responsiveGrid">
            <container
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="capstone/components/container"
                layout="responsiveGrid">
                <title
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2022-11-21T08:34:26.857+05:30"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    jcr:title="AbstractReferences form the backbone of any medical literature. Presently, because of high inflation, it is very difficult for any library/organization/college to purchase all journals. The condition is even worse for an individual person, such as private practitioners. The solution lies in the free availability of full-text articles. Here, the authors share their experiences about the accessibility of free full-text articles.Keywords: Free full-text article, research work, accessGo to:INTRODUCTIONPresently, in India nearly 314 medical colleges are providing undergraduate medical education in the form of MBBS, 163 colleges are providing doctor of medicine in diploma in Dermatology,Venereology and Leprosy (DVL), and 84 colleges are providing diploma in DVL.[1–3] In addition to this, 27 hospitals are providing diplomate of national board in diploma in Venereology and Dermatology.[4] On comparing this data with number of research articles published, the latter stands in a mediocre situation. One of the important cause responsible for the relatively less number of research publication is unavailability of free full-text articles. Research works, published by most of the journals, are paid. Many of the undergraduates or postgraduate students may not be able to purchase these high-cost journals or articles. In addition to this, many researchers may not be willing to spend money on journals. These are some of the situations where free full-text articles come for rescue, but many of the beginners may not be familiar about how to search these articles. In addition, free full-text articles are the first choice for many of the postgraduate students for their dissertation.Go to:HOW TO APPROACHIn addition to journals which are fully Open Access, there are few other journals which operate through subscriptions as mainstream journals do, but which offer open access to the electronic versions of their articles after a delay of usually a year, or selectively for individual articles, provided the authors have paid an additional charge to “open up” the articles.[5]Free full-text articles can be approached in the following ways.Medknow PublicationsMedknow Publications publish nearly 150 journals. They provide free access to the electronic editions of their journals.[6] Researchers just have to open the site www.medknow.com, fill the key word they require, and search. Alternatively, they can visit the search option, available in most of their journals site through www.journalonweb.com, fill the key word, and search across multiple journals. At times, this site alone provides sufficient number of references required for the purpose. The important dermatological journals published by Medknow Publications are Indian Dermatology Online Journal, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Venereology, and Leprology, Indian Journal of Sexually Transmitted Diseases and AIDS, International Journal of Trichology, and Journal of Cutaneous and Aesthetic Surgery.[7]PubMed Central and PubMedPubMed Central is the United States National Library of Medicine's digital archive of biomedical and life sciences journal literature which provides free access to the full text of articles.[8] To search for free full-text articles on PubMed Central, one has to visit the site http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/, write the topic/author/journal title, and search across all articles.PubMed is a database of citations and abstracts for articles from thousands of journals. PubMed does not include full-text journal articles.[9] It includes links to full-text articles at many journal web sites as well as to most of the articles in PubMed Central.[10] Here, articles can be searched on the site http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed. Search can be restricted to contents free on web by using filter your results and clicking free full text.[11]Directory of Open Access JournalsThe directory aims to cover all open access scientific and scholarly journals that use a quality control system to guarantee the content.[12] It provides articles from 439 medicinal journals. Among them, 21 are from dermatology.[13] It includes Anais Brasileiros de Dermatologia, BMC Dermatology, Case Reports in Dermatology, Clinical Dermatology, Clinical Medicine Insights: Dermatology, Clinical, Cosmetic and Investigational Dermatology, Dermatología Peruana, Dermatology Online Journal,th Dermatology Reports, Dermatology Research and Practice, Egyptian Dermatology Online Journal, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprology, The Internet Journal of Dermatology, Journal of Clinical and Experimental Dermatology Research, Journal of the Egyptian Women's Dermatologic Society, Open Dermatology Journal, Revista Argentina de Dermatología, Surgical and Cosmetic Dermatology, Turk Dermatoloji Dergisi, Turkderm.[14] The disadvantage of directory of open access journals is that few of these journals are in languages other than English. Here, articles can be searched on the site http://www.doaj.org.Electronic Resources in Medicine Consortium and National Medical LibraryElectronic Resources in Medicine Consortium (ERMED) and National Medical Library (NML) are an excellent platform for obtaining free of cost recent journal articles for its member colleges. There is no membership fees charged from the Government Medical Colleges and institutions. The private colleges and institutions have to make payment per site price for e-sources purchased by the consortium in every calendar year.[15] Membership of the college can be checked from the site http://www.nmlermed.in/members.htm or volunteers can contact their library to check the membership and to get the user name and password of the site www.ermed.jccc.in allotted to their college.[16] In 2009, the number of ERMED members increased from 40 to 72 Government Medical Colleges/Institutes across the country.[17] At present, it covers nearly 32 journals of dermatology. It includes Acta Dermatoveneorologica Alpina, Pannonica et Adriatica, Acta Dermatovenerologica Croatica, Advances in Skin and Wound Care, American Journal of Clinical Dermatology, American Journal of Dermatopathology, Archives of Dermatological Research, Archives of Dermatology,, Asian Journal of Dermatology, BMC Dermatology, Clinical, Cosmetic and Investigational Dermatology, Clinical Dermatology, Contact Dermatitis, Dermatologic Surgery, Dermatology, Dermatology Nursing, Dermatology Online Journal, Dermatology Times, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Indian Journal of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprology, International Journal of Dermatology, Internet Journal of Dermatology, Journal of Drugs in Dermatology, Journal of Investigative Dermatology, Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology, Medicine, Open Dermatology Journal, Pediatric Dermatology, Rosacea Review, Skin and Allergy News, Skin Pharmacology and Physiology, Turkdem-Archives of the Turkish Dermatology and Venerology and Turkish Journal of Dermatology.[18]Journal articles related to the topic can be searched easily after signing in at the site www.ermed.jccc.in, followed by clicking search database.Google, Google Scholar, and Yahoo"
                    sling:resourceType="capstone/components/title"/>
                <container
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="capstone/components/container"
                    layout="responsiveGrid"/>
            </container>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
    <article--1/>
    <article---2/>
    <article---3/>
</jcr:root>
